Timofey Belousov

LinkedIn | GitHub

Location: Saint Petersburg, Russia

Email: <u>btima@mail.ru</u> | Telegram: <u>@imodre</u> | Mobile: +79538598353

EMBEDDED DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled embedded developer with over 5 years of experience in microcontrollers.

As a 3rd year student in CT department of ITMO University I am studying computer science.

With an experience with many popular platforms like AVR, ESP, STM and with single-board linux computers, I've done **dozens** of full stack embedded projects from scratch in my freelance career. Some of my projects include *CV*, real-time concurrency, networking and many more technologies. Feel free to read through some examples of my projects. I've also included some embedded school and pet projects below.

SKILLS

Languages : C/C++, Python, Java, Kotlin, Rust, C#, Swift, Verilog, Clojure, Prolog, Haskell, JavaScript

Frameworks: PlatformIO, ROS, FreeRTOS, MQTT

Platforms : MCU: AVR (ATMega/ATTiny), ESP32, ESP8266, STM8, STM32. SBC: Raspberry/Orange Pi, NVIDIA Jetson

Dev Tools : JetBrains IDEs, VSCode, Arduino IDE, Postman, Git, ŁTĘX

Soft Skills : Time Management, Leadership, Public Speaking

Spoken Languages: Russian (Native), English (Fluent, C1)

EXPERIENCE

Embedded DeveloperApr 2018 – Present

Freelance

Remote

DESIGNED AND DEVELOPED FROM SCRATCH:

- CNC machines using C++ with controlling software written in C#
- CAN analyzing and statistics device for VW cars
- Concurrent cellular networks analyzer and logger with GPS tagging using C++ and FreeRTOS
- Ultra Low Power GPS tracker with audio recording and online configuration features (C++, PHP, MQTT, FreeRTOS)
- Animated LED staircase with online configuration feature, modular hardware design (RS485, C, C++, HTML/CSS/JS)
- Autonomous hardware intrusion detection system (C++)
- Sensors communication libraries according to manufacturer datasheets
 WORKED WITH:
- Many popular protocols: *UART, I*²*C, SPI, CAN, RS232/485, etc.*
- Integration of DL models within my own CV stack for perception
- Linux-based servers and single-board computers
- EDA + CAD for hardware design
- Full hardware + software project support
- Real-time operating systems within multi-core MCUs for protocol implementation, raw audio/video stream processing
- Hardware debugging tools and different electronic test instruments

Teaching assistant

ITMO University

Sep 2023 – Present Saint Petersburg, Russia

- Teacher's Aide at Advanced Operating Systems course
- Prepared and gave a lecture on topic "Applied cryptography and hardware methods of providing the information security" within the Advanced Operating Systems course

EDUCATION

ITMO University

Bachelor of Computer Science - Applied Mathematics and Informatics

Saint Petersburg, Russia Sep 2021 – Present

Center of Teaching Excellence's School

Computer Science

Moscow, Russia Sep 2020 – Jun 2021 ADAS + DMS transport complex Python, CUDA, PyTorch, OpenCV, C++, Java, PostgreSQL, 3D Design, PCB Design Website

- Designed for safe and efficient cargo transportation for freight companies
 - Tracks:
 - * Car and driver status and behaviour
 - * Current road conditions and alerts the driver and operator when needed
 - * Driver fatigue and attention
 - * Car health via the CAN bus
 - * Driving style via the acceleration G-sensor
 - * Air conditions inside the driver's cabin
- Includes hardware intellectual property protection system

Chess board with an integrated chess computer

Python, C++, 3D Design, PCB Design

Project Files, Source Code

- · Arduino as an MCU communicates with the board sensors and indicators
- Raspberry Pi implements the generic Chess game logic and runs Stockfish as choosable game opponent
- 3D Printed game figures with an integrated magnet for automatic figure position identification
- CNC Engraved chess board
- 3D Printed chess board's chassis to include all the electronics
- · Custom PCB with individual LEDs at each board cell for indications and shift register ICs for addressing them

Smart Schoolbell

C#, ASP.NET, MVC

Project Files, Source Code

- A bunch of speakers mounted all over the school building (usually instead of old-fashioned schoolbells)
- A webserver connected to all the speakers is deployed in the server room
- Admin has the access to web interface. He can upload any audio file on each of the planned bells
- System support planned notification playback
- Flexible lessons schedule for the whole week
- · Choosable playlist to play during the break

AwesomeVPN

Kotlin, Telegram, Bitcoin, Spring, PostgreSQL

Telegram Bot, Source Code

- Wireguard-based VPN platform
- Telegram bot UI
- Blockchain subscription model with acceptance of cryptocurrency payments

UAV as a weather station

C++, ROS, Python

- · Arduino-based weather sensing unit
- Fast data collection and analysis
- Autonomous data collection according to the prepared flight plan
- · Capable of performing autonomous cargo delivery

Line following autonomous vehicle

Python, OpenCV

- Robotic chassis with camera installed
- Uses CV to steer the vehicle along the line, solving the given task

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Absolute winner of Intelligent Robotic Systems track in NTI Contest (SLAM, Python, ROS, OpenCV)
- <u>Winner of Higher School's of Economics's electronics competition "Vishaya Proba"</u> (Arduino, C++, Hardware Engineering)

PUBLICATIONS

• USE OF UAVS FOR REMOTE AIR QUALITY MONITORING: COLLECTION OF ABSTRACTS OF THE PARTICIPANTS OF THE XIII ALL-RUSSIAN CONFERENCE OF STUDENTS "NATIONAL HERITAGE OF RUSSIA" VI ALL-RUSSIAN YOUTH FORUM "AGRO-INDUSTRIAL COMPLEX – YOUTH, SCIENCE, INNOVATIONS", p. 688, ISBN 978-5-4491-0262-1